Gayathri Satheesh

A highly-motivated student currently pursuing M.Sc. Computer Science with specialization in Machine Intelligence at Digital University Kerala (previously known as - Indian Institute of Information Technology and Management, Kerala).

Thirivananthapuram, Kerala, India +91 8606026888 gayathri.mi20@iiitmk.ac.in

EXPERIENCE

IIITMK, Thiruvananthapuram — *Student Intern*

MARCH 2021 - PRESENT

Developing deep learning algorithms for transpilation.

NeuroAGI, Digital University Kerala, Thiruvananthapuram — *Graduate Research Intern*

MARCH - PRESENT

Researching in Cognitive Architectures.

Google Cloud India — GoogleCloudReady Facilitator

APRIL 2022 - JUNE 2021

Facilitated over 300 students from various universities within India, helped them in upskilling in the cloud domain.

Freelance — Full Stack Web Developer

AUGUST 2020 - MARCH 2021

Designed and developed efficient and maintainable software according to business objectives and needs of various clients.

EDUCATION

Digital University Kerala , Thiruvananthapuram — Masters' *Degree*

SEPTEMBER 2021 - CURRENT

MSc Computer Science with specialization in Machine Intelligence

Mar Ivanios College, Thiruvananthapuram — Bachelors' *Degree*

JULY 2017 - JUNE 2020

B.Voc. Software Development - 8.6 cgpa

AWARDS

Second Runner-Up, South Zone Inter University Youth Festival, Western Guitar -2019

Second Rank, B.Voc Software Development, Mar Ivanios College, University of Kerala, Batch of '20

LANGUAGES

English Hindi Malayalam Tamil

Christ Nagar EHSS, Thiruvananthapuram — 12^{TH} *Standard*

JUNE 2015 - MARCH 201

Higher Secondary Education - 91%

PROJECTS

Face Detection based Attendance Registering System — Computer Vision

Developed and optimized Computer Vision based project that detects faces of the students and employees, and register their attendance automatically into the attendance register.

E-learning website — Full stack web development

Developed and optimized website using MERN stack. The website aggregates courses from multiple e-learning platforms.

Legacy Systems Modernization — *Machine Learning*

Implemented machine learning techniques to convert assembler code to target high level language.

Programming Languages

Python, JavaScript, Java, C++, IBM HLASM

TOOLS AND FRAMEWORKS

MERN Stack, JQuery, Flask, Django, Streamlit, Google Cloud, Flutter, React Native

VOLUNTEERING ACTIVITIES

Rotaract Club — *Member*

National Service Scheme — Student Volunteer